PAOLA VINCENT

pvincent@feaverslane.com | (709)749-1949 | Petty Harbour, NL | March 2021

SPATIAL ANALYSIS & CONSERVATION PLANNING PROJECTS

- Historical VHF Marbled Murrelet Datasets (in progress): Contract for Environment and Climate
 Change Canada to assemble historic VHF datasets of Marbled Murrelet movement based on the
 collection performed from 1998 to 2002 in Clayoquot Sound and Desolation Sound, British
 Columbia. Data was collected across many different sources and compiled into datasets to be
 shared on Movebank. Sources were quality checked and where necessary processed to derive
 location tracking data previously not available to scientists.
- Habitat Restoration Sites Prioritization (in progress): Multi-criteria prioritization using GIS
 analysis and local/expert knowledge to rank suitable capelin, salmon, and char habitat
 restoration and enhancement sites. This is an update to an earlier prioritization analysis and
 incorporates additional field knowledge and extensive work on beaver dam site candidates to be
 outfit with a beaver baffler / flow device by World Wildlife Fund (WWF) Canada and partners.
- **Fisher's Knowledge Transformation:** Digitizing 3Ps cod fish harvesters' knowledge of cod fishing practices and changes over time. Fishing grounds and associated information were mapped by harvesters on large format paper maps. Digital spatial data and recommendations on survey methods were delivered to the Fish Food and Allied Workers Union.
- Labrador Coastal Characterization: Digitizing coastal characterization for the Labrador coast to be published in a Coastal Risk Assessment report and NL Geoscience Atlas, and used to support identification and prioritization of coastal habitat restoration sites by WWF Canada and the NunatuKavut Community Council.
- Conservation Plan Analysis: Analysis of environmental variation representation across
 existing and proposed protected areas on the Island of Newfoundland using ArcGIS Pro
 and Excel. Analyses and summary report were incorporated into a Canadian Parks and
 Wilderness Society official submission.
- Marbled Murrelet Tracking and Sea Surface Temperature: Contract for Fisheries and Oceans
 Canada entailed analysis of satellite sea surface temperature (SST) in raster format of 16 areas
 over the years 2012-2018 in the waters surrounding Vancouver Island. Software used was
 ArcGIS and Excel. Statistics, data spreadsheets, maps, graphs, workflows, and summaries were
 all created as deliverables to project head researcher and correlated with tracking/movement
 information for Marbled Murrelet and their prey.
- Coastal Change Assessment: High-resolution mapping of beach systems in Conception
 Bay which required both field work and post data processing. Assisted in gathering
 remote sensing and elevation data and transforming raw data into comprehensive maps.
 UAV/drone, ROV and surveying equipment were used in the field, and Agisoft and ArcGIS
 were used for post-fieldwork processing.

Cost Path Analysis for Caribou Corridors: An independent GIS term project exploring cost path
analysis for animal corridors. ArcGIS was used to map anthropogenic activities and Woodland
Caribou species range near Jasper National Park. This area had two ecologically important
regions for the caribou that are fragmented due to human activity. Cost path analysis tools were
used to estimate the least energy pathways where Woodland Caribou could cross over major
roads to connect the ranges.

EMPLOYMENT

February 2021 - Present

Geographic Information Systems Consultant, Feaver's Lane Enterprise Inc.

Providing spatial analysis, digitization, prioritization, reporting, and related services for clients in natural resources, environment, and conservation sectors.

December 2019 February 2021

December 2019 - Geographic Information Systems Analyst, Independent Contractor

Collaborated with and mentored by Randal Greene of Feaver's Lane Enterprises Inc. as a GIS Analyst on a per-contract basis.

May 2019 - July 2020

Research Assistant (Field & Laboratory), Department of Geography, Memorial University of Newfoundland

Assisted in the gathering and processing of coastal elevation data and beach assessment with lead researcher Brandon Tilley and project managers Dr. Rodolphe Devillers and Dr. Norm Catto.

May 2019 -March 2020

Server, Bartender, and Host, Bernard Stanley Gastropub

Filled many front-of-house positions at this very busy restaurant with Gastropub atmosphere.

October 2014 -March 2019

Food and Beverage Supervisor, Bartender and Sever, *Exile Restaurant at Jag Hotel*

Started as a server and was promoted to position which included many managerial responsibilities at this higher-end hotel restaurant and lounge.

EDUCATION

August 2019

Bachelor of Science (Major in Geography, Minor in Biology), *Memorial University of Newfoundland*

Focused on physical geography, geographic information systems, conservation, and marine biology.

- Completed numerous projects in **ArcGIS**: digital terrain models, 3D geovisualization, geocoding, vector and raster analysis, etc.
- Holds Esri certificate for 6-week online training of cartographic concepts using ArcGIS Pro
- Holds Esri certificate for 6-week online training of Spatial Data Science using ArcGIS Pro
- Knowledgeable in **QGIS** Software
- Familiar with **R** Software
- Attended the Geomatics Atlantic 2020 workshops and conference offered through Canadian Institute of Geomatics
- Completed numerous high-resolution elevation surfaces in Agisoft
- Trained in **TileMill** for designing web-based basemaps
- Used **UAV/drone** and **ROV** technology in numerous field sites
- Experienced with RTK GPS equipment in surveying
- Competent in discovery, acquisition and editing of spatial data
- Completed field courses in a variety of Newfoundland environments
- Holds **Open Water Diver** certificate
- Holds Basic Drone Operations license
- Experienced with recreational and sea kayaking
- Extensive management, communication, problem solving, and customer service skills